# Anders G. Nordby



# https://www.linkedin.com/in/agnordby/

anders@delichon.no

Eiksveien 82, 1361 Østerås, NORWAY

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Systems Architect and Senior Developer with 20+ years of experience designing scalable software solutions across industries. Specialized in application security, distributed systems, and modern architecture. Proven leader in team coordination, agile practices, and security governance.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

05/2019 - PRESENT

Delichon AS

# Systems Architect & Senior Developer

**Customer:** Element Logic **Duration:** 5 years

Roles: Senior Systems Developer, Security Champion

**Technologies:** C#, Akka.NET, Blazor, REST, GraphQL, NHibernate, SQL, NUnit, Moq, Microsoft .NET Standard, ASP.NET, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Git, Powershell, Kiuwan.

**Responsibility:** Senior developer on Element Logic's main product, eManager. Additionally, focuses on application security, and is the initiator and leader for Element Logic's Security Chapions Guild.

Customer: ABB

**Role:** Senior systemutvikler **Duration:** 6 months

**Technologies:** Azure DevOps, Azure DB, Azure WebServices, Akka.NET, TypeScript, React JS, C#, Microsoft .NET Core, TFS, Git, Powershell.

01/2018 - 04/2019

Sopra Steria

# Lead Software Engineer

**Roles:** In-house architect responsible for planning and QA of offers to customers. Senior developer for some customers.

Customers: Skatteetaten, Helsedirektoratet.

**Technologies:** C#, .Net, Episerver CMS, ASP.NET MVC, Microsoft SQL Server, JavaScript, Jira, Confluence, TFS, Git.

03/2014 - 08/2017

**CGI** 

## Senior Web Developer

Roles: Team-leder, scrum master, hands-on architect.

**Customers:** ASKO, Fellesforbundet, Tekna, PIA, Miljødirektoratet. **Technologies:** C#, inRiver PIM, Apptus eSales, Episerver CMS, Episerver Commerce, IdentityServer, T-SQL, NServiceBus, Jira, Confluence, jMeter, BlazeMeter, Angular.js, Knockout.js.

03/2010 - 01/2014 08/2008 - 12/2009 02/2006 - 07/2008 10/2004 - 02/2008

05/1995 - 06/2002

Making Waves, Senior Systems Consultant Creuna, Consultant / Systems Developer Ocelluz, Systems Developer & Project Manager Anders Nordby Konsulenttjenester Ajilon, Consultant

# **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Processes

Systemarkitektur, Scrum, Kanban, prosjektledelse.

Development

C#, Akka.Net, GraphQL, NHibernate, Blazor, Gherkin, Specflow, Cypress, NUnit, Moq, DoxFx, Docker, Swagger, Kiuwan, PowerBI, log4net, Episerver, ASP.Net, T-SQL, PL/SQL, Javascript, JSON, NServiceBus, REST, WebAPI, XML, HTML, CSS, Powershell, LATEX.

Tool

Jira, Confluence, TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, Git, TFS, SubVersion, NewRelic, jMeter, BlazeMeter, NuGet, Kiuwan.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

202I	Certified Optimizely Developer
2020	Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

2019 PRINCE2 Practitioner

2019 Certified Scrum Master

2018 PRINCE2 Foundation

## **COURSES**

2024

'	8 11	8 8	
2019	Tom Gilb: Architectu	re Workshop	
2018	Sopra Steria: Arkitekt	urskolen	
2015	Microsoft: Lead Enter	prise Architect	Programme

Building an AppSec Scanning Programme

## **EDUCATION**

2003 – 2004	University of Oslo, Teacher Training	
1999 – 2000	Oslo Business Academy, IT Candidate	
1987 – 1996	University of Oslo, Cand.Mag.	
1984 – 1987	Eikeli High School, Natural Sciences	

#### **AWARDS**

2013-2017 Episerver Most Valued Professional

### LANGUAGES

EXCELLENT	Norwegian (native), English
INTERMEDIATE	Bulgarian, German
BEGINNER	Spanish, Japanese